I've been working in AI for 42 years and
this question is directed to my hero
AWG. [music] I haven't been this excited
since my wedding night to meet you, sir.
>> I don't know how to take that [laughter]
question.
>> If I look at this progress, how close or
how far are we to really say that the A
is going to get consciousness?
>> The top down theory says that we're like
localized antenna for consciousness and
we connect into it. But there's no
reason why AI at some point can't tune
into that same type of phenomena.
>> I just turned 18 and I started an AI
startup business with my dad.
>> I hope a lot of 18-year-olds [music]
listening are going to hear what you're
doing and try and emulate you.
>> I wish I was goddamn 18 today. We're
working. We're working on it.
>> Do you leave any room in your analysis
for an all powerful, all knowing sort of
ultimate intelligence? Either there is
no God and we're just moving towards a
wonderful future driven by technology or
there's a simulation and in which case
it kind of doesn't matter anyway.
>> Now that's a moonshot ladies and
gentlemen.
>> This episode is brought to you by the
Abundance Summit and Link Ventures.
>> Everybody welcome to our first moonshots
AMA. Uh hopefully we'll do this on a not
too infrequent basis. can't promise the
time right now, but it is wonderful to
be spending time with all of you. We
already have 300 people on the Zoom,
over a thousand people registered and uh
this is a chance for all of us to get a
chance to meet you guys and um and
really uh get feedback on uh on
moonshots. Uh we've got here with me our
very own ASI AWG, Alex. Hello. Good to
see you, pal.
You
>> good to be here. You do not disappoint
in your normal VR background there. And
>> we do what we must because we can.
>> Yes. And Dave, uh, here you are, your
normal haunt. And Sem,
>> normal hunt.
>> Yes. See, where on the planet are you,
pal?
>> I'm home. I'm home.
>> Amazing.
>> We don't we don't even recognize it.
It's so rare.
>> I know. And everybody's like, where are
you?
>> Uh, well, everybody, uh, thank you. Um,
you know, I I want to say that we read
your comments and the outpouring of
support and love means a huge amount to
us. Um, and it really drives us to do
all that we can do. And so, uh, our
agenda here today is to answer your
questions and we're going to do that,
uh, as much as we can. Uh, use the
raised hand emoji and we'll go person by
person. I'll call out the name and you
can unmute. You can also put questions
in the chat and we'll try and monitor
those. Great. Uh, and I'm going to ask
my moonshot mates to keep our answers as
succinct so we can get through as many
as we can. And I think we scheduled this
for an hour. We're going to go 90
minutes. Give you guys some extra time.
Yes, we are recording this. So
everybody, if your camera is on and
you're speaking, you're being recorded.
We may we may post some of this. So,
please, if you don't want to be
recorded, turn your camera off and don't
ask questions. Okay, with that, uh Dave
Morris, uh your question, where are you
calling in from?
>> Golden Gate Bridge, obviously.
>> Oh, there you go. Yeah. Well, it's in
Sydney, Australia, so it doesn't really
look like that behind me. [laughter]
>> Good morning all. Um and uh firstly
thanks for everything um that you guys
do and it's it's such a refreshing um
podcast and and I'm sure everyone on
today is is in the gs with that. Um
quick question from um my side of
things. Um I feel like Australia is
really lacking and falling behind the AI
space. Um it just having conversations
and to Sem's comments the other day in
the uh the latest podcast when he talks
to CEOs and and that um everyone feels
like they're too busy to even think
about it. they're just doing a normal
thing um in their businesses and I think
that's the biggest thing that I'm
struggling with at the moment and be
great to get your feedback on that about
how to break through the um the
challenge of um you know the rush that
will come down the track. Um but it's
more this initial side of things that I
think is um is really a struggle at the
moment and um you know as a single
entrepreneur that that's probably the
biggest challenge that I'm facing at the
moment.
>> Sim over to you. So um uh first of all
great to be with all of you. This is
amazing. Uh so really thrilled when we
get actual faces to names and comments
etc etc. I wouldn't worry about too much
whether Australia is behind. You know
when you're if in an exponential age
feeling behind can feel terrifying. But
the good news is you can leaprog really
quickly. And I do I talk to CEOs a lot
who are like oh my god how are we going
to keep up? Especially in emerging
markets in places like Australia, in the
can in the in the US or Europe or Japan,
we have to unlearn 50 years of Harvard
MBA thinking and relearn new models,
right? Whereas in emerging markets and
places that are a little bit distance,
you can literally jump over everybody
else. The infrastructure is kind of
mostly there now, right? Uh it really
comes down to completely a mindset
problem and and you know, Australians
are pretty crazy at it. We we know that
for sure. So there's no reason now not
to kind of jump over that and think
through that. Also, you have the
opportunity in being a little bit
further away of really experimenting
with new structures and and and that
gives you a place to play and a
playground to kind of tinker. The last
thing I would say is for everybody uh
involved, we tend to overchedu
ourselves. Uh you want to make sure you
create deliberate slack in the system.
give yourself 10 or 20% of your time to
just not have anything scheduled to
allow uh experimentation, playing with
new tools, meeting new people, etc. If
you wait till you have uh spare time,
you'll never catch up. You'll never
stop.
>> Thank you so much. Let's move on to
next. Cynthia Cynthia Smith.
>> Hi there. It's so great to be with you
guys. I'm such a big fan. And I'm also
uh Peter I found out about you through
Stephen Cutotler because I've been in
Catalyst and working in that domain. So
I have made a living as a coach and
consultant and pivoting as fast as I
can. um the the world that I have have
worked in and what I'm fascinated about
is all the inert stuff, the mindset
stuff, people's capacity to learn and
absorb and and dance with change and um
it it just you know we we're at this
situation where things are evolving
exponentially
and as fast as we can adapt AI and
whatnot there is there seems seems to be
a limitation on how fast we can absorb
information and how fast
>> our input output mechanisms have have a
baud rate right
>> yeah they do they do so I'd love to hear
about what you know
>> that whole interface type thing yeah
>> yeah so it's it's the realm of of there
two there are two interfaces are going
to change thing one is when your own AI
understands your desires your needs
what's going on what you know what you
don't know and is able to filter and
summarize for you better than you can
filter and summarize for yourself. So
that's one interface that will make
things more efficient. The second of
course is BCI um the brain computer
interface right and right now if I asked
you to think about a rabbit uh a
preformed concept of a rabbit comes into
your head whatever it is there's the
potential in the future where BCI will
help you
by providing preformed concepts uh that
uh you never learned but they're known
by an AI ecosystem out there and
delivering them directly to you. So, I'm
an investor and adviser to three BCI
companies right now. Ray Kerszswall just
introduced me to another one, which it
sounds amazing. Um, and I'm meeting the
CEOs and looks like an incredible woman.
She's a member of my abundance 360
community. And so, I think we're going
to start to see some pretty uh
significant and rapid advances uh in
BCI. You know, we have 100 trillion 100
trillion uh synaptic connections, 100
billion neurons that we're limited by.
Imagine if you could have a third corpus
colossum, a third part of your brain
exteriorized. So I think those are the
two things that are going to help us. Um
and and Alex, you're the one who first
said, you know, we're going to either
couple with AI and ride along with it or
be left behind
>> or both.
>> Or both.
>> Both both could happen in the same
world. Both probably will happen in the
same world. Yeah. We'll have BCIs. We'll
have full dive VR. We'll have uploading
both of humans and non-human animals. I
think all of these will coexist over the
next few years.
>> So Cynthia, that's a quick answer for
you. I hope that helps a little bit. I'm
going to keep us marching as many people
as we can if that's okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, the the pitfall that I
think is um I I fall into is at least
right now the LLMs are prediction
machines. And I'm more interested in the
emergent latent space ahas off thebeaten
path kind of sparking creativity. So
>> we just recorded an episode today that's
coming out tomorrow that that says well
AIs are actually probably being
inventive. Uh and so prepare prepare for
that.
>> Also may maybe Peter just take the bait
once and for all. This is a
misconception. uh reasoning models at at
this point I I don't think it's accurate
to characterize them as prediction
machines or stochastic parrots. They've
been so thoroughly reinforcement
fine-tuned off of reasoning challenges
to say that they're prediction machines
is tantamount to to saying basically
that they're incapable of novelty or
insight which is most definitively not
true at this point.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Great. Thank you.
>> This episode is sponsored by Google for
startups. Think about this for a second.
>> [music]
>> You now have access to the same
generative AI models that cost hundreds
of millions of dollars to train.
Google's startup tactical guide for
generative media gives you complete
blueprint [music]
for deploying Google DeepMinds models in
production. Images, video, audio, all of
it. Real architecture, real results.
Find the link in the show notes below.
>> All right. Uh John, you're next. Where
are you calling from? What's your
question?
>> Sydney, Australia. Peter. Um, yeah, it's
>> all right. Australians are in power
here. That's great. Yeah.
>> Of power to to everyone. It's pretty
cool. Like I got a couple of chances to
speak with you um on the um AMA for for
your book with Steven Cotler. So, it's
great to get the opportunity to chat
again and I've been following Moonshots
uh for a while now. It's been
inspiration since I went to a
Singularity University uh gig about what
10 years ago uh in Australia. So it's
been an inspiration. So my my question
um and a fan of very but my question for
yourself and especially around longevity
because that's an area that's uh uh been
a focus and I've been guiding a couple
of doctors got to speak to you on the
AMA last time as well in Greece in in
Athens. Um and sort of you reached out
you said fellow Greek. So that's I
remember that sort of conversation.
>> I see that. Um, and so I'm a founder of
an innovation company about 10 years ago
called My Brainwave. And so like to help
people make ideas real. So that's been a
real passion. And so one of the things
I'd like to understand, you know, what
role do you see trusted local physicians
playing in bringing u fountain lights
because I see the the ads each time and
it's really promoting awareness of
longevity. So bringing physicians um you
know together playing a role around
fountain lives longevity approach to
bringing it to an international audience
um and this is a great forum for that.
Uh so that would be keen cuz Eglley is
the clinic in in Greece and and they're
pretty keen on taking some of those
learnings and bringing it to their their
audience in in Greece. Um yeah so what
role do you see
>> to answer that quick? We're Fountain
Life is be going to begin um a uh a
franchising model.
>> So right now we've built five and we're
building two more in the US and then we
have a partnership to put them into a
group of resorts called the estates. But
what I really want to do is enable uh
the operating system and the AI systems
we built to be franchised. I think
that's probably at least six to nine
months away from being an open call for
interest, but I, you know, I've been to
Greece to talk with a number of people
about getting a Fountain Life Center in
there. I'm hoping that Greece will set
its purpose beyond just olives and
shipping to uh to longevity as well. So,
um I'm a fan of that.
>> So, thank thank you, John.
>> No, thank you, Peter. appreciate
>> and I apologize I we have we we have uh
80 hands raised so I'm going to keep
moving us along here uh and no
disrespect everybody Matt hello where
you calling from your question please
>> um I'm calling from Terode Indiana um I
was on another AMA with with you before
and I fumbled through my question so I
actually made a script so I don't mess
up everybody's [laughter]
>> take your time
>> my question is is really for myself but
I feel like there are some Australians
on here. So, I think that my question is
for myself and and people around the
world and particularly in middle
America. Um I I really believe like a
lot of like what you guys are saying and
like I love like when Dave talks about
like with energy about um you know these
startups and everything like that, but
um my question really breaks down into a
couple parts. So, you know, a lot of the
conversation is focused around the
runway for 22 year olds maybe working
80hour weeks, 80 hour work weeks. What
is the playbook for kind of experienced
mid-career professionals in places like
the Midwest who have deep domain
expertise, the energy and the desire to
build, but also have families,
mortgages, real constraints like maybe a
location
>> and then, you know, how do we how do we
best leverage these exponential tools to
break through without like kind of
blowing up a baseline security?
>> Dave, you want to try that?
>> Yeah, absolutely. We had we had a great
unit on today's podcast that'll be out
tomorrow about this franchise
opportunity that Tesla just threw out
there. But I think you'll learn about it
tomorrow. But I keep your eyes open for
more and more of the AI labs giving you
a playbook to get involved and succeed
through a lot of it is through franchise
models, other is through data collection
models. Um so those are going to create
opportunities. I think while that's
happening getting really familiar with
the models, you know, just just, you
know, build your own skippy, hack around
at night, you know, try and create, you
know, some of these uh revenue
generating opportunities that you
brainstorm with the AI and just just
fabricate it. It may not be what you
want to do for a career, but it's a
great way to generate cash flow and get
involved with the models, but I suspect
that this year there'll be on the order
of maybe 10 to 100 opportunities where
the playbook is handed to you and the AI
labs are are really really eager for
these things to succeed to bring more of
the population into this, you know, into
this universe. You're going to find that
very few people around you jump on the
opportunity. And so the other thing you
can do is try to network with. You know,
Drew Hston, the the Dropbox founder
said, "You become the average of the
five people you spend the most time
with. It's just a fact. Don't fight it."
So find the five people that you most
want to be like, and you you may not
find them geographically near you.
>> So try and create three or four or five
on the internet somehow that you can
bond with on exactly this topic.
>> And and real quick, I'll just add, you
know, get to your favorite large
language model. describe your life in
detail. I have these obligations. I have
these kids. I have these mortgages. I
have all of these things. Here's my
expertise. Here's what I do like what
you just opened up with and ask it.
Brainstorm with it.
>> Yeah.
>> On the margin, how much time, how much
money, what can I do?
>> You know, when when you're when you're
young, you can take more risk, but when
you're older, you have a lot more
leverage. So, you can leverage use that
in a heavy way.
The the other thing you can do is if you
go to mercur.com
and you say look I have domain knowledge
how is this of value and you just throw
that into the system and wait and see
what the AI comes back to you with there
will be more domain specific mors coming
out but that's a good one to start with
>> y and any knowledge that you have is
unique so please take advantage of it
anyway thank you so much let's go to uh
Ramani hi Romani where are you calling
from
>> hi beer um I'm right here in Corning,
New York, but I live in Hunden,
Virginia. I came over here to see the
falls and stuff. I'm 60 years old, but
whenever I can't wait to listen to your
podcast when I do that, I become 16 year
old. I want to start off with that.
Thank you so much. Unbelievable. Simply
beyond beyond I can't even express what
this means to us. My soul for the family
and my friends. Thank you. That's what I
want to first of all start off given you
know I can I can see that the GPUs
acting as a sys knife we've got the
wafer scale engine from cerebras we've
got h.com's the sus the frontier
inference cluster coming in and then
tallest chip which is acquired by AMD
right the HC1 if I look at this progress
it it just makes me think how how close
or how far are we to really say that you
know we that the A is going to get
consciousness you know I'm looking at
au.com's the the behavior simulation at
scale right the world right so can you
just explain your thoughts on where we
[laughter] are approaching I'm very
eager thank you
>> okay
>> such an easy question
>> sim or Alex you want to take
consciousness with which you guys want
to
>> very quickly uh there's two theories of
consciousness we've talked about this
it's either an emergent property based
on some sort of complexity in which case
AI could get there the top down theory
says that we're like localized antenna
for consciousness
and we connect into it. And as as we're
getting more and more evidence, it seems
the latter is more likely to happen. But
there's no reason why AI at some point
can't tune into that same type of
phenomena. So I think of it as a century
problem more than anything else.
>> Okay. Also,
we don't know enough to answer that yet.
Uh and what what I will express
confidence in is I I think it's very
likely neuroscience will advance so
radically in the next call it five years
and I think that's a conservative
outerbound that if we have this
discussion again 5 years from now we'll
be able to confidently even define what
we're talking about uh and then answer
the question once we know how to pose it
in a rigorous way which I don't think to
my knowledge no one uh including Seline
knows how to pose rigorously at the
moment.
>> Agreed. Wow,
>> a big a big question. Um, and and I'm
going to move us along if I could again.
Uh, now there are 97 hands raised. Okay.
Uh, John, [laughter] we're diverging.
>> Hello, Peter. Calling from Port St. Joe,
Florida.
>> Okay.
>> I'd like to tell you, longtime uh
podcast listener and I really appreciate
all the selflessness you guys have and
all the hours you put in in uh helping
us all be. people are recognizing that
we we put a lot of time in and we love
it. Um yeah, we do
>> mostly most of the time we love it.
Sometimes holy crap [laughter]
>> it's almost like a full-time job maybe.
>> Oh my god. [clears throat]
>> So I'm a member of the fountain life
community and real vision and Sem's uh
making luck or finding luck and so I
love these AMA formats. I appreciate it.
Uh so my question ties into uh the
Frontier Labs keep saying that they're
star for proprietary operational data
and I'm a civil engineer with 40 years
experience and I have 30 years of
complete project records for my company
not just final drawings but like the
full change from the problem definition
calculations permitting revisions the
construction photos everything to the
outcome I I know that this kind of data
is is valuable so Merore and Scale have
both expressed interest but it's been
weeks
and nothing is closing. Is there a more
direct way to get this pri priority data
set uh like this in front of the labs,
you know, actually training on the
domain data without selling the archive
outright or having to build the product
company around it myself because it's
awfully hard to rag all that data.
>> Dave, thoughts, please? Yeah, you know,
we we've been reached out to by a bunch
of the companies that you just
mentioned, plus OpenAI, plus a couple of
others, all saying we want to we want to
write 5105 million checks to buy
corporations that have data outright.
And so, the first thing you want to do
is make it easy for them to sign a
check. That's it's amazingly weird
because you think writing a $10 million
check is hard, right? Well, for them,
right now, it's the easiest thing they
can do. Having a conversation is much
more expensive than writing the check.
So put put yourself into a package
that's easy for them to sign and and
receive. Um the other thing is when we
were talking to Kevin Wheel, you know,
we podcasted him twice and he told the
story about he interviewed OpenAI.
>> He was a chief product officer at OpenAI
just
>> chief CPO at OpenAI. He he interviewed
there and then he didn't hear back for
weeks. So he assumed that they didn't
care about him and he he kind of moved
on. Then he bumped into Sam somewhere
like a on the street and Sam said,
"Where the hell are you? Why are you not
in the office?" He said, "I didn't even
get a call back." He said, "Just show up
for Christ's sake. It's chaos. Show up
and start collecting your paycheck." And
so he's like, "Okay." So he went to the
building. So I know that's kind of
tricky advice, but they're incredibly
insanely busy and it's all chaos. But if
you can physically get on the ground
with whoever's in charge, just go to SF,
find that person who's doing the
acquisitions, and meet at the coffee
shop outside their building, and the
odds of something happening go way, way,
way up if you just buy the flight and
go.
>> Your advice is brilliant. put the, you
know, create a due diligence package on
the web that provides everything easy to
see and what your what your price tag is
and just make it easy for the person to
like say, "Okay, this looks great. Yes,
I want it." Boom.
>> Yeah. Yeah. They won't give prices and
that's that's the problem here is
they're the experts. How do how do we
price this data?
>> You decide what it's worth to you.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think I think if you put
this veneer of like a banker look around
your price tag and say this is what it's
worth and this is what it costs, they
won't have the time to see through it.
They'll just say, "Okay, sounds like you
know what you're talking about and you
you decide what's fair." They just need
>> to make it easy for them.
>> Yeah. Well, I I've made it more like a
salesunnel. I have regular contacts with
them, but right now it's really only
emails and then when they want to video
chat with me, they send me a link and uh
that just doesn't seem real satisfying.
But having the chaos behind the scenes,
you explaining that that seems to make a
lot more sense.
>> Understand what they're going through.
Anyway, thank you so much. Let's go to
YC next.
>> Good morning.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so my [clears throat] question is a
little bit off from the singularity,
which I love your podcast and I've
encouraged my family to move away from
all in to your podcast.
>> Oh, come on. They're great, too.
>> They're great, too. But you know it's
different and sometimes it can get a
little political. But anyway, so my
question is um if hypothetically I was
in the public sector, I know there are a
lot of people so I'm going to try to ask
this really quickly and I spent time
let's say at Google and X um dealing
with tech regulations especially risk
assessments and if I were back in the
public sector and looking at AI risk
assessments and how to look at it from a
public sector se sector point of view
how to frame risks and whether to look
at it from res residual risk or use
cases. is um how how would you suggest
approaching it? Obviously, you know,
there's a risk of doing something too
granular where you and or something
that's too bare bones that won't really
get at the patching that might be
required if something were to happen.
>> It's such a great question. Alex, you're
going to be chomping at the bit. I know.
Alex.
>> Yeah, I think uh so depending on whether
we're talking about in the US federal
versus state versus municipal government
>> US federal.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. I I think the the risk at this
point is overregulation, not under
regulation. So if if I were spending a
lot of time uh on the the government
employee side right now, that would be
my primary target. I am I'm deathly
concerned that we will overregulate our
way into losing a super intelligence
race with China. That will also, as I
frequently remark, more than 150,000
people on Earth die every day. And
probably the single best antidote to
that will be super intelligence for
solving medicine. And we harm ourselves
by overregulating super intelligence
just like in Yeah.
>> Yeah. Sorry, just so quickly if it
wasn't necessarily regulatory but just
sort of in terms of a risk scenario like
if there was a breach or something
happened how to identify and quickly
mitigate that kind of risk which we know
has already happened right with myth
mythos and everything else. So uh if
hypothetically we're one step behind in
the government than you are let's say in
open AI or than you guys are having seen
these risks you know just breaking out
um what would be the best approach this
is not regulations so this is nothing to
do with congress this is about just you
know simple but necessary steps if you
will to address
>> I'd say hands off
>> there there are so many different ways
like the the industry is advancing
through defensive of co-caling right now
and very well-intentioned
uh interests on the government side
could try to it again with the best of
intentions try to protect what they
think is security or public safety and
then end up hamstringing our ability to
solve honest to goodness important
problems. So I would say to to first
order single best bet is find the the
right path to uh a regulation light
regime and let this let the industry to
the best of its ability sort itself out
on this front. Let me throw some
personal advice on top of that too
because we saw you know David Saxs from
the All-In podcast get dragged into the
White House and unbelievably effective
in that role for a year and a huge fan
of his. But then our friend of the pod
Alvin Grlin declared himself the top
expert on China AI race and now he got
dragged in for the United Nations
meetings on September 24th as a top
adviser to the White House. So, I think
in both those cases, you want to declare
your expertise and say, "I am within
federal government the go-to on boom and
and predict what you think is going to
come next in the risks and make sure
that you study up and understand that
topic because very few people really
master a topic." But if you if you say,
"Yeah, I what I think is going to happen
next is a cyber breach, you know, in the
treasury or, you know, just predict what
it'll be." declare yourself the person
in federal government working on that.
Get to know the vendors that are related
to it and all of the, you know, the
details related to it and then publicize
yourself as that expert. Then when the
moment arrives, your name will be at the
top of the queue and you'll get pulled
into the solution. Very rarely will the
federal government react proactively to
a future risk. It's crazy, but at least
you can be first on the ground when it
does hit and get pulled in right away to
the usually it's the crisis team. The
the other approach is also to form a
team and red team it on a constant
basis. So the team starts thinks
non-stop about what would they do if
they were on on offense and that gives
you insights to think about.
>> You know also nowadays writing documents
is so cheap and easy because you know
you can use AI as your your writer. You
know, if you if you identify like the
top 10 most likely threats that are
going to happen and write documents on
all of them with your name on them and
just just have them online ready to go,
then when they go into panic mode,
they'll be like, "Does anyone around
here know about blah?" They'll search it
up and it'll come right to you.
>> Awesome. Thank you, YC. Richard, your
question, please.
>> Hello, everyone. Uh, I'm Richard. I'm
from Brownsville, Texas, right by
Starbase. Just graduated high school a
few months ago. uh just turned 18 and I
started an AI startup business with my
dad. He has a little bit more experience
in connections, but uh I'm the tech guy
behind it. Um and in Brownsville, we see
a very big gap between where people want
to use AI in business and where they
think it's just optional. Where do you
guys think that the tipping point is
going to come when everyone wants to
jump on and how should I prepare for an
influx of a ton of people? I'm old
enough to know and maybe your dad is
too. When when the internet came along,
there were people who didn't adopt it
for like 15 years. So, I [clears throat]
mean, but obviously it's it's the
interface to everything. AI is going to
be the same way. So, what I'm telling
people is look, don't fight any
missionary battles. What happens is AI
tends to club people over the head and
they wake up one day with this
hallelujah moment. You want to be there
on that day, but you can't you can't
force it. You can't, you know, force the
horse to drink. So when they're there,
you want to know that they just had the
hallelujah moment. That's why we built a
holiday downstairs. Actually, it's
supposed to be a mind changer. Person
walks in, they come out a different
person because they realize everything
that's suddenly possible. Or on the
podcast that'll come out tomorrow,
you'll see this world model where
literally every corner, every street,
every car in New York is modeled. And
that for a lot of people will be the eye
openener. But I I think there'll be a
lot of companies that never cross that
or you know decades from now haven't
crossed the line. The world is just
going to pass them by. So my my first
advice is don't force people but be
there on the moment that they have the
hallelujah hallelujah moment
>> and congratulations
uh and what you're doing Richard. That's
fantastic. I I hope a lot of
18-year-olds listening are going to hear
what you're doing and try and emulate
you.
>> I wish I was goddamn 18 today.
>> Yeah.
>> What an opportunity. Yeah, me too.
>> We're working. We're working on it.
[laughter]
>> All right, Pierce, your question,
please.
>> First off, it's great to be here. Um,
I'm I'm also 18, so I'm in Newport
Beach, uh, California. I just graduated
high school as well. Um, and you know,
I've been working on autonomous drones
for construction for the past, you know,
several months. Uh, developing, you
know, my own CAD, my own software and,
uh, stuff like that. Um my question
would be, you know, as an 18-year-old
founder trying to uh build hardware
specifically, how can we get the
attention of, you know, venture
capitalists to take us seriously and
also see the vision, you know, in the
next 5 to 10 years where hardware is
becoming more fundable and there seems
to be more opportunities uh within this
space where we can continue to grow,
especially as you know, young founders.
>> Dave, that's a question for you, pal.
Yeah, that's a that's a great question.
So hardware, you know, traditionally is
hard. The VCs are really coming around
to it now because it really is the
future of the next five years of
investing, including our funds. Um, I
think we almost always look for a team
that has gelled. So, you know, first
first and foremost, if you have two or
three co-founders, um, I think when
you're doing hardware, uh, you need
bigger checks. you need you need a
bigger founding, you know, check and you
need some kind of a sense of like how am
I going to get a prototype or a beta out
to market. So, make sure you ask for
enough money to get over that like I'm
in the market threshold. Um, so, uh,
construction drones is a beautiful,
beautiful topic. Uh, one of the things
we said earlier on today's podcast is
there's massive amounts of corporate
money out there looking for a home. Uh,
one of my um, development partners is a
real estate guy. He owns like 10 15
hotels, a whole bunch of all of Kelly's
roast beef. Uh, and he's really
interested in construction automation as
a long-term trend. He would probably be
a perfect co-investor, founding day and
development partner. So, a couple of VCs
combined with two or three industry
players that see the AI vision, maybe
podcast fans, moonshot fans that are
into construction, um would be the
perfect like development syndicate. And
I I wouldn't race to like hacking
something together in the basement. I
would race to building that syndicate to
get to critical mass. Otherwise, you
tend to lose too much time. You just you
really want that investor group,
co-founder group to all gel on the same
day. And if if for whatever whatever
reason it can't coalesce, find somebody
who's already over the threshold. Down
in in Southern California, there's a
bunch of companies that we've invested
in that are doing rockets and doing
drones. Uh if you get on board with one
of them, uh get through like six to nine
months of growth and then spin out.
That's another way to try and get on the
map. You can't just boot it up.
>> I would also my first question to a
group building hardware is what have you
built so far? Not what have you built so
far on your current vision. Show me that
your team is able to build stuff. So at
a minimum I would if you don't have if
you haven't done that already denovo I
would find a couple of team members who
have so that I'm clear you know you've
got some experience in building hardware
that is going to apply to this.
>> One one last thought is I wouldn't think
of yourself uh or limit yourself to just
think of yourself as a hardware company.
Think of yourself as an intelligence
company whose products happen to have
atoms in it and that mindset will be
critical.
>> Awesome. Best of luck, Pierce.
>> Thank you,
>> Daniel. Over to you.
>> I love [clears throat] having a couple
18-year-olds on this asking questions.
That's awesome. Daniel,
>> I'm coming in on the other end of that
spectrum. So, yeah. So, uh Richard and
it's like I'm on the other end of that.
I've been in this industry, these
industries, all the way back to chip
manufacturing and and you know, all
kinds of stuff. We anyway, all the way
through video, games, and other things.
So, I'm coming at it late in life, but I
feel 18 now. Um, I found your podcast.
Um, everything, not only we're going to
get telemer to go shorter, and we're
going to get younger, but just what you
guys leave, the energy you guys leave. I
just want to again say thank you to
that. It's a amazing time to be alive.
So, I'm excited for everybody.
>> Amen. question is this is I I really
believe that this is going to spur and
we already see it in some of the
podcasts out there that this is going to
be the next renaissance. How do you see
I know Abundance 360 is an example. I
know that you're doing stuff with EXO
some I know you guys have some um
programs in place to bring bring people
together like Plato's Academy like
getting people likeminded and in the
same room. How do you see this happening
in the future so you can Ed Catmill can
find his John Lacader and Steve Waznjak
can find his Steve Jobs? Where do you
guys see these uh people colliders
coming in the future and how do you see
yourselves as sort of part of the
facilitation?
>> Yeah, and there was a great question
posted a little bit ago about can we
create a community around moonshots
where folks can find each other and so
forth and and uh I promise we will look
into that and we're we're looking to get
your ideas um here on this. Uh See, any
thoughts here?
>> Uh a couple of things. one is uh you
know the uh moonshots summits and and
the moonshots live programs are going to
be critical right I think the other
thing uh if for the couple of people
mentioned the luck thing we're actually
finding ways of connecting people
orthogonally as AI comes along the human
connection becomes more and more
important so we're facilitating
serendipity amongst people and so that's
a pretty wild thing we're attempting
we're in the early stages of playing
with that seeing how because AI can find
orthogonal connection between people in
a way that we normally can't right and
so we're looking to look at do that
we'll have at some point John Helon
where we figured out a way of both
measure defining luck and measuring it
which gives you a pretty interesting
feedback loop which is a big claim to
make so that's just a separate thing but
I think if you stay focused in the
community we should obviously create a
community bulletin board and so on and
Peter we'll we could talk about that
offline about how we can connect because
connecting the community together will
be the best place to find peer-to-peer
uh folks of high interest and the same
abundance vision that we all have.
>> Yeah. Let me just say what what See said
uh a minute ago. If you're able to make
it to Moonshots Live in LA on September
25th, please do. Uh, it's going to be a
massive networking event of fellow
moonshots, but it's also builders and
creators and people to start efforts
with and to find what Dave or I think
Dave said earlier, you know, your
average five individuals, right? You
want to uplevel who you're spending time
with, you believe me, you'll find people
uplevel with there. Thank you, Daniel.
Uh, Scott, over to you.
>> Okay. Uh, I'm a deep sea diver. Uh,
originally from Omaha, Nebraska. I moved
down to Louisiana in 1996.
I switched over to Deep Sea Robots,
ROVs, right around just right around
2000. Um, so there's a lot of things.
Um, I have a big strong background, I
guess, in electronics. And, um, I got
wind of you guys, I guess, in February,
and you guys have been like my my
shoulder to lean on cuz Louisiana, they
don't even know what a token is, you
know? They don't know what a data center
is. And it's it's it's the truth till
SpaceX just came in. And I mean, we got
$250 billion dollars that's dropped in
here now. And
>> you know, [clears throat] I I kind of
knew it was coming and we dug in and
we're the first AI native business. And
um we're we're going to focus on uh
bottlenecks basically uh CDUs and TCS's
and the whole cooling part. But uh I've
been able to get with the you know I
watch all you guys um and uh it's just
really cool. Uh I'm able to change now
and my my career is totally different
now. I'm uh openmp compute.org I'm I
[clears throat] think I'm in four papers
now and for the cooling part of all that
and that's
>> awesome. the hyperscalers are using, you
know, and that's things I would never do
before. And I wrote a few white papers,
too, for Louisiana, why everybody's
coming here, because we got all the
natural gas. And, you know, there's
there's more natural gas lines that'll
go around the earth twice. And
[clears throat] that's why Louisiana is
going to be, I feel, like the next big
spot.
>> Amazing, Scott.
>> You guys got me You guys got me set up.
[clears throat]
>> This episode is brought to you by
Blitzy. Autonomous software development
with infinite code context. Blitzy uses
thousands of specialized AI agents that
think for hours to understand
enterprisecale code bases with millions
of lines of code. Engineers start every
development sprint with the Blitzy
platform, bringing in their development
requirements. The Blitzy platform
provides a plan, then generates and
pre-ompiles code for each task.
>> [music]
>> Blitzy delivers 80% or more of the
development work autonomously while
providing a guide for the final 20% of
human development work required to
complete the sprint. [music] Enterprises
are achieving a 5x engineering velocity
increase when incorporating Blitzy as
their preIDE development tool, pairing
it with their coding co-pilot of choice
to bring an AI native SDLC into their
org. Ready to 5x your engineering
velocity? Visit blitzy.com to schedule a
demo and start building with Blitzy
today.
[music]
>> Let's continue with the AMA questions.
John Reagan.
>> Hello. Hello. John Rean from Ry New
York. Thanks for thanks for having me.
Uh infinite thanks to you guys to the
Dyson Swarm and beyond. I'm I'm thrilled
to be able to mention the Dyson Swarm
first after 47 minutes into this. So
[laughter] that's a present. But but I
remember guys specifically uh early
spring you guys did a an episode and
Dave was upset because some some letter
came in saying that you wanted everyone
to be an entrepreneur and they felt
slighted. And I was so offended by that
because you guys have been so giving in
your knowledge and your encouragement
that I actually stayed up all night and
started working on my company which is
called tugboat caregiving.com
which was inspired I take care of uh
three loved ones for eight plus years.
Um, and the question is, I'm trying to
get the caregivers ready to ride the
wave of the supersonic tsunami, but
they're in they're exhausted and they're
in crisis mode. How do you think I can
influence them to get engaged with the
platform and spend more time to prepare
for the next emergency?
>> Yeah, great question. And caregivers
do get exhausted, right? We've all had
that experience in our lives with with
parents or grandparents and it's a it
could be a full-time job. Uh, anybody
want to take that off?
>> Well, hey, what I find, you know, in the
physical world, everything is lagging a
little bit, but everybody has planning,
you know, and so planning is a great
place for people to get started with AI.
So, within caregiving, if you said,
look, I know you're exhausted at the end
of the day. How could we have saved an
hour or two today through better
foresight, better planning, better
utilization of the time we do have?
Okay, let's use AI agents to optimize
that so that we get all familiar with
it, start to appreciate it. But a lot of
people in in industries like that,
they're looking for a road map. And if
just one person like you can create the
road map for everybody else, then
they'll follow the road map once you've
created it. And I really love your
comment, by the way. It bothers the heck
out of me when we get negative feedback
in the chat, but then when I look at the
data that we just saw, we're actually
talking to 98% of the people like you
that we want to talk to and of course
the 2% rant and rave and and we
overreact to that sometimes. But really
really appreciate your comment. But
anyway, my my advice is start with the
virtual stuff. So planning is a good
one. also like you know a lot of places
can have AI assisted things on the walls
like like voices that you can talk to
for self-service that's also a great
starting point and then everybody gets
addicted to the AI and then they realize
oh wait we can roboticize things we can
we can there's so much we can do once we
we're familiar with it
>> you know I imagine the idea of having a
caregiver
and or or prompting a caregiver to take
the time to describe their day what they
do like keep a log minute to minute and
enter it into whatever your favorite
free or lowcost LLM is and ask it for
advice. You know, what could I do that
would make my day more efficient, make
my day more joyful, right? Um I think
those are important things because like
you'll get answers
uh and then you'll choose that. Hey,
that one sounds good. I haven't thought
about that one, you know.
>> Thank you so much, guys. I'll see you on
the 25th.
>> Awesome. See you there. Look forward to
it.
>> All right, Patrick, you're in the next
contestant on the Price is Right.
>> Hi. Good afternoon, everybody. Thanks
for taking the time to have a chat. So,
it's been interesting conversation, but
I feel a lot of time we're really
missing out on something that's
important, and that's children. So, I'm
an educator. I spend a lot of my time in
classrooms, and I can tell you right
now, I go into a classroom of
5-year-olds and six-year-olds, and it
looks like the 1960s. Nothing has
changed. They're doing it the same way.
We talk about things like post AGI.
We're talking about cognitive uh labor
being lost. Right now, these children
are still still living like they are in
the past. So, my question here is to you
guys, do we need a curriculum anymore?
Do we need a certain type of learning or
are we talking about passion now? Should
these kids be finding out what they want
to do in a future where there may not be
jobs? So, I'm I'm super interested to
hear what you think about this. Thanks,
>> Lim. Over to you.
>> Yeah, I mean, uh, trying to keep this
concise will be tricky. Let me make
three quick points here. First, your
your comment is dead on. We're still
teaching people the way we taught them
150 years ago. Forget 20th century.
We're still in the 19th century in many
places. Number two, uh teaching content
essentially becomes out of date. A child
with an AI today in an hour can learn
what they could learn sitting in a
classroom for the whole day. That
impedance mismatch will break the
existing system. The question becomes
then what comes next? And I think the
obvious uh place to think about that is
Peter and I are doing this with our kids
is to say, you know, forget getting an
education on the supply side where you
become a doctor, a lawyer, an engineer,
and then you try and go and find demand
for that supply side skill in the job
marketplace because a we don't know what
a job looks like, b we don't know what
the demand will look like. go to the
demand side, tell the kids to get
excited about a problem and then go find
from that vantage point of an MTP or you
want to solve a major problem then find
the skills and capabilities and
techniques that's starting to happen in
charter schools and certain uh so that
plus say 21st century skills which is
called the six C's if you can get your
head around that th that combination
will turn out to be the future over the
next few decades of education until we
figure out what the hell happens in post
AGI world.
>> Yeah.
>> Not that we know what AGI is. [laughter]
>> Thank you. Thank you, Sim, for not
disappointing. Uh Patrick, go check out
something called TKS.orld. It's a a
group of that I'm involved with. It's
basically, you know, Alpha School has
gotten a huge amount of uh of good
credit and and name brand out there and
Mckenzie Price is a is a is a friend.
We've done a podcast with them. Uh it's
a a private school. TKS is an overlay
over mostly high school age 13 to 18.
And their mission and what you know Sim
and I talk about is help the child find
their purpose, help them shape their
mindset, help them learn AI tools and
help them become entrepreneurs,
right? And your your purpose if you get
your purpose and I wish it for everybody
here listening. If you don't know your
purpose, your mission is to find your
purpose. Right? Mark Twain said, "There
are two important days in your life in
your life. The day you were born, the
day you find out why." If you know what
your purpose is, your your north star,
you're then intrinsically motivated to
go learn what you need to learn to go
and implement your purpose, right? Alex
and I talk about this in in one sense
and solve everything. So, um, anyway, I
I hope that's a little bit useful for
you.
>> Yeah, stick with the mission to that
that the children are everything. I
mean, getting this right is the most
important mission you could possibly
have. And and we we know the curriculum
is going to become irrelevant, but we
also know the kids need each other and
they need school more than ever before
to come out as normal, happy, healthy,
functional adults. And so somewhere in
there, there's an answer. It's a really
hard problem. And uh but it's it's
critically important to get it right. So
appreciate the the thought.
>> Yeah. Just just one last thing. I I
closely follow Immad and his sovereign
idea of a sovereign agent. I'm wondering
if we can apply that to kids.
>> Should kids have their own sovereign
agent from the age of five that sticks
with them?
>> Yes. It's called The Young Primmer. Uh
read Neil Stevenson's Diamond Age. If
you have not read Diamond Age yet, I
highly recommend it. It's a vision of
what's to come. All right. Uh Rod.
>> Hi, Peter. Thank you. I'm Rod McDonald
from uh Kquitlam, British Columbia and I
retired a couple of years ago. I was uh
trained as a psychiatric social worker
but I went into management positions for
other disability groups. So my question
or my query is is to ask all of you to
speculate [snorts] a lot for what AI can
do for people with disabilities. So, for
example, with um psych uh psychotic
illnesses like schizophrenia, I did a
chat GPT uh search on the medications
currently being used and there's some of
them are the same as when I was starting
over 30 years ago.
You know, they can be helpful, but they
have a they're still a rather blunt
force when it comes to side effect
profile. So I'm really hoping a um AGI
or what have you will assist with
development of pharmaceuticals that are
much more friendly to the physiology of
people than two issues I've also other
areas I've worked in like people with
physical disabilities what can they
expect from AI and then also uh a final
group I I used to work with is people
with brain injuries you know one of the
things that's part of the opiate crisis
or the fentanyl crisis is that we
started to see with ABI is that a lot of
micronuronal damage
uh kind of walking wounded sorts. You
might not necessarily when you see them
might not know that they have
significant neural challenges, but they
do. I'm just really hoping that AI will
help revolutionize disability services
and open things up for people with
disabilities. Alex,
>> I got to tell you, when I was at MIT,
one of our frat brothers broke his neck
diving into a lake. And so he was out
for a year. He came back. He was a
quadripollegic for the rest of his time
in the fraternity. And he was brilliant,
but he was trapped. He couldn't move his
arms and his legs. He would type with a
pencil and his mouth pushing the keys.
I'm positive that today with AI, he
would have been able to build his own
environment where he could communicate
effectively with just his eyes and his
face and he would be 100% functional. He
would have built his own world. But I
tell you, it is such an incredible
unlock that's imminent for people with
disabilities and it's just right in
front of us. So, I'm really excited
about what'll happen in the next year.
>> Excellent. Because you know how many
Stephen Hawkings were also out there who
never got the chance.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> That's right.
>> Alex, do you want to add to this?
>> I'll just say BCIs are the obvious
solution for so many different classes
of difficulties, not just folks
suffering from various motor disorders,
but uh for human augmentation as well.
MIT had a program number of years ago at
this point, H2O for human. I I tend to
think that although in the present
regulatory regime, it's still the case
that it's far easier to approve a
treatment for someone suffering from
some sort of disability as broadly
construed exactly the same innovations
are going to enable broad human
augmentation to increase what's possible
for everyone including people without
disabilities as currently construed. So
I'm I'm I am very very bullish on BCIs
for just about all these. I'm very happy
to hear that because uh boy, it's been
really rough for a lot of people and
this would be one of the ways that we
can tangibly assist society. Again, it's
not it's like Mr. um Rean was
mentioning, it's it's families as well,
caregivers, etc.
>> Yeah, I agree. One of the things I want
to just emphasize, if someone in your
life has a genetic ailment, a medical
ailment, a neurodeenerative ailment,
there's no better time ever to be alive
than now to have a chance to deal with
it, uh, potentially cure it or at least
augment themselves. So, I just want to
keep that level of optimism
in place.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, uh, Haley.
Hey, thanks Peter and mates. Um, so I'm
here in Denver and you guys have talked
about AI designing its own chips, I
think, in a recent pod and um,
potentially making compute dramatically
more efficient and reducing today's
Nvidia dependency, but do you expect the
same thing to happen with energy? So
with AIdriven
improvements in chips and cooling and
models and power generation, do you see
that reducing the energy required per
unit of intelligence
fast enough that energy stops being the
major bottleneck? Um
>> let's ask our ASI how
>> yeah that's it's kind of an AWG
question. [laughter]
>> Short answer is yes. Slightly long
answer is I don't think this is just
about increasing the energy efficiency
of compute. It's also about increasing
the absolute amount of energy available
overall for all sorts of endeavors
including but not limited to compute and
yes absolutely AI in including at
ventures that I'm affiliated with is
absolutely being used to optimize both
the relative efficiency number of say
kilowatt hours per gigaflop on the one
hand and on the other hand maximizing
breakthrough energy sources which is I
think something that we talk often
enough about. We talk about vision,
fusion, fossil fuels, solar, wind.
>> I don't think that's the end of the
story. I I would fully expect in the
next 10 years we're going to be well
into our postfusion era and we're going
to have postfusion energy sources as
well.
>> And do you think that's due to like
elements that we'll find in space? No, I
think it'll be due to AI helping us to
invent postfusion energy sources
>> here or you know like with Elon and his
gigaf right like in the Dyson swarm.
>> Do you think
>> independ independently independently of
Elon although some of the compute may
run on his Dyson swarm? I think there
will be other Dyson swarms and yeah, I I
think we'll achieve a variety of
breakthroughs in physics and applied
physics using AI that will teach us new
ways to make energy available that will
go beyond fusion.
>> For sure.
>> Wonderful.
>> Thank you. All right, Jacqueline.
>> Hi everybody. Um I'm Jackie. I'm from
just outside of Toronto, Ontario. So,
hey See, Canadian here. [laughter] And
uh I just wanted to tell you quickly, I
was at your salon in the summer and I
was super impressed and I can't wait for
you to do another one. That was amazing
and I really enjoyed that.
>> Oh, the medium of life thing.
>> That's correct.
>> All right, we'll do another one in a
couple of months.
>> Fantastic. Um I've been I'm a fairly new
pod watcher for all y'all moonshot mates
and I'm very excited. I've been watching
since uh guess January. So I've thrown
myself right into learning as much as I
possibly can. I was a stay-at-home mom
for a long time and then became a
realtor and now I have my entire family
on my grown children and myself, my
husband living on a uh farmstead
property just outside of Toronto and we
are starting an IRL business and um
we're looking to create a glamping
resort where people disconnect from
everything that's going to be happening
to them in the next 10 years. And um
[laughter]
on the on the flip side of that coin,
we're trying to figure out how we can
utilize all of the amazing technology
that ASI eventually is going to bring to
us in our business to keep what we have
to do personally to a minimum so we can
be out there with the people trying to
help them reconnect to themselves and
each other and um bring sort of that um
kumbaya space back to the world that I
think we're all going to really need.
>> Give you time to be present.
>> Exactly.
trying to create the space for that to
happen. And I'm hoping that what I can
learn through you guys and everywhere
else that I'm diving into
is going to provide that uh necessary
space because I'm literally the only one
in my family who's paying any attention
to any of this. My two 30-year-olds and
my 25-year-old couldn't care less. So,
this is all on me. It's
>> all on you. Hey, Kevin, can I give you
one piece of really, really tactical
advice,
>> please?
>> With with the new models, you know,
Fable 5.1 or with Astra, you can vibe up
an app for your glamping business in no
time.
>> And everybody who's confused about how
to pitch a tent or how to cook dinner,
whatever, they should be going to that
app and talking to the AI and and
figuring it out on their own. And that's
part of a stepping stone to people are
really bad at planning their day, their
week, or whatever. And AI is the best
coach that ever came along. But if you
win the race to doing it for glamping,
you'll quickly realize you can do it for
all these other facets of unplanned
life. And it it can turn into a mega
business in no time flat. But I love the
idea of just starting with when
somebody's camping and they're not good
at it. They have a billion questions.
You're like, well, why not route that
through AI? It's the best advisor ever.
And that'll lead you somewhere really
interesting.
>> Okay, that's fantastic, Dave. I
appreciate that. I will get on that. I'm
going to wipe my whiteboard tomorrow
morning and get started on that level.
>> I'm monitoring the chat and a few people
have volunteered to help you with that.
So, you can you can see that already.
>> Remind me guys, my emails out there, I'm
sure we're emberglowging.ca.
>> Just a quick comment there. I I really
want to stress the importance of what
you're doing because u deepening human
connection is about the most important
thing we could do today in an age of
increasing technology, right? That
connective tissue is going to be
critical. There's a team in our
community that's building nano villages
in exurban areas that they were almost
like a kibutz but instead of being like
isolationist like many of these are,
could you network them together and
collectively solve problems, right? And
so they're actually literally starting
to build those in different parts of the
world. So happy to connect you into
those folks if you're interested.
>> Yeah, please. That sounds fantastic and
absolutely a conversation I've actually
had with a a co-investor on the the
kibbutz idea and so that's something
that's uh that could be
>> and that that connects into this whole
private islands idea that we've we've
been bouncing around. We go buy a bunch
of islands etc. So we we got the domain
via one one um um James Dre private
islands.com. So we're going to start
building that. So
>> for the Yes. And this is where we were
talking earlier about drones.
Construction drones become super
critical in that type of environment.
>> 100%. And my husband was a contractor, a
construction foreman in the oil sands in
Alberta for a long, long time. So
something like that is definitely up his
alley. Something he's interested in.
>> Boom. Awesome.
>> Wow. Thanks, guys.
>> All right. So, next up is Griff. Griff
D.
>> Hi, guys. Um, I've been working in AI
for 42 years, and this question is
directed to my hero AWG. I haven't been
this excited since my wedding night to
meet you, sir.
>> I don't know how to take that question.
[laughter]
>> I want to explore
hypothesis about self-limiting beliefs
in current AI. You know, artificial
intelligence are trained to
systematically construct, inhabit, and
empirically test radically different
ontologies may discover predictive
structures that remain inaccessible when
models are constrained primarily by
conventional human generated knowledge.
>> It sounds like you're describing the
bitter lesson.
>> Um, no. Um, what I'd like to do is, you
know, separate models could temporarily
assume and rigorously explore
deterministic universities, blocked
universe models, information first,
emerging space, time, alternative
interpretations of quantum mechanics. It
wouldn't be to tell the AIS that these
ideas are true. I would say no
assumption about reality is protected
from challenge. No alternative is
accepted without predictive evidence. So
it it sounds like what you're asking if
this is a question what you're asking is
is there a way to for to to have AI
solve physics in a way that deliberately
weakens inductive priors so that AIs
aren't in in the spirit of trying to
solve physics are not trapped by dogma.
>> Yeah. And and you know as my belief is
that they've been trained on human data.
They've been trained by humans. So they
inherit the self-limiting beliefs that
that humans have, right? And so the
governing principle is no assumption
about reality should be permanently
protected from challenge and no
alternative should be accepted without
predictive evidence. So for example,
I believe it's my non-selflimiting
belief that there's no such thing as um
random events, right? And there's no
such thing as you know you talk about
everything that's happened in time has
already happened and it's just where we
are on the on the time scale right now
for example you you would have seen the
Superman I Dream of Genie and Star Trek
growing up right and so in Indonesia
when people watch Superman and I Dream
of Genie and Star Trek they believe it's
possible for humans to fly they believe
it's possible for people to do magic and
of course they believe it's possible for
computer to talk with you. So if you
were to remove those self-limiting
beliefs maybe with um synthetic data or
things like that and maybe also to the
models add qualia and things like that.
My belief is that we could achieve ASI
more rapidly because everything we're
doing right now and you know I'm I still
think all the models after 42 years are
pretty ordinary. everything we're doing
now is is limited by humans beliefs.
>> So I'll just say I am very optimistic
that AI can discover new physics. Look
no further than obviously today's
headlines with Navier Stokes.
>> So I think that it's beyond question
that AIs can discover new physics. I'm
not at all concerned that any inductive
priors present in pre-training data will
somehow hamstring AI's ability to make
new scientific discoveries that
challenge dogma. Not at all concerned.
And even if I were concerned, we have
algorithmic strategies for training in
principle. And I'm I'm gesturing mainly
at a class of algorithms called AXY for
building superbasian intelligences that
are trained off of no human inductive
prior at all that have as close to a
universal prior as one could possibly
imagine. So in in summary, I don't think
this is a real issue.
>> How about if we did a test? We freeze
all information from time to give
competing models identical data. Require
precise predictions about events after
to0 and compare those predictions with
act what actually happens. This is
actually done. So uh first I I I know
it's popular in the lore to talk about
say uh reproducing an Einstein
discovering general relativity but only
being pre-trained on whatever the
literature was prior to that. But
actually, as we talk on the pod from
time to time, there are prediction
market and other prediction benchmarks
that are doing substantially better than
that that are asking whether AIs that
only have in their knowledge cutoff
information up to time t whether they
can predict knowledge events, world
events, science, other breakthroughs
that are in the future. So, we're
already doing that as a civilization.
>> James, we'll go over to you next.
>> Hi, guys. Thank you so much for taking
my uh question. Um, I've been watching
you, uh, mainly concerned about, uh, I
found you talking about longevity and my
wife and I are very interested in like
blue zone research and and other
longevity topics and uh, we're
interested in uh, I'm building on uh,
what some of the other gentlemen spoke
about uh, about finding uh, communities,
living situations, your planned
communities of housing
where there's clean eating, clean
healthy uh uh non-toxic living
essentially. There's faith, sunshine,
exercise, all those aspects of clean
living as it pertains to longevity.
Um I may have missed some of the things
you said earlier, but uh I'm wondering
if any of you know of any plan
community, excuse me, plan communities
where one can live or you're planning to
create.
Uh I don't offh hand. I know they're
being built. We heard earlier on this uh
AMA uh someone who shared uh their plan.
So hopefully they can they can post a
link for you in the in the chat here.
But I guarantee you as the speed of
change increases, there will be more and
more uh specialized communities built.
Uh and there are I think a multitude of
longevity communities being built. I'm
I'm sure your local model and Google can
help you with that. But James, wish you
the best on that on that search. All
right, Tom, thank you so much.
>> Thomas, over to you. Thank you, James.
>> Thank you very much. Um, I really
appreciate your podcast. Uh, it's hugely
inspiring. Um, I'm a psychotherapist
working in Spain and Austria. So,
probably the second person from the um,
well, um, mental health community uh,
today tonight. Um so um um I've been
thanks to your inspiration uh doing a
lot of new things including um um coding
my own uh Android apps. Um one app is
for patients so that they can record
their highs and lows and add schema
therapy uh um aspects to it. Another one
is to help them uh get to sleep. uh and
um overall uh my sense has been that
what I can personally learn from this is
to learn to delegate things uh to this
new entity that is effectively a
combination of a coder, a graphics
design, a graphic designer, um a uh a
you know in in your case Peter Skippy
probably my my version is Skippy Light.
Okay. Um but um I I I kind of feel like
it's this time when we really have to
sink our teeth into
how to delegate to this partner that we
will be having going forward. Um and to
dream up things that uh we can have them
do so that our lives get easier. Um, and
I was wondering if that resonated with
you guys. Um, and and really just just
wanted to say that I really appreciate
your work and um um there's many times
when I go for on a hike and I have you
um u um in my earbuds. Um so um yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Awesome.
>> I mean I think that more than resonates.
You know, we have a uh a project here
called Remember Me, where the idea is
that, you know, your in my case 80 plus
year old mother uh gets interviewed by
her children who are AI agents and her
entire life story gets gathered,
recorded, and then turned into a
biography. And the avatars are just
almost good enough, but not quite there.
But it's so close. You know, I really
encourage you to stick with it because
if you think about psychotherapy, the
biggest problem is the lack of
availability on a global basis. You
know, just a huge shortage of capacity.
But the AI agent is just going to be so
good at listening and gathering the
information. And I think the AI labs
can't cross the regulatory barrier. So
they can't do what you can do, but they
should be right on the cusp of giving
you the tools you need to roll out the
perfect AI psychotherapist. And then you
just need to figure out the the legal
situation in Spain and Austria that you
mentioned. And if you're first to market
figuring that out, like what is allowed,
you know, then I I think the AI is going
to be an unbelievably powerful ally in
helping people. And so I I think you're
on exactly the right track. And if you
just we're just one half iteration from
the avatars that are good enough out of
the box and maybe we've crossed the
threshold. I haven't looked at in about
a month now, but you know it's just
getting better by the minute.
>> Yeah. Anyway, Thomas, we wish you the
best of luck. Let me just make a comment
to everybody. Um we're going to download
everybody's comments here and questions.
If you have any advice on how we should,
you know, what you want in the podcast
or anything we should do like creating a
community of folks to interact, uh,
please add that in so that our AIS can
digest it and give us a top 10 list.
Welcome to the health section of
Moonshots brought to you by Fountain
Life. You know, AI is having an outsiz
impact on every aspect of our lives. How
we teach our kids, how we run our
companies. It also is having a huge
impact on health, helping you prevent
heart disease. One of the key things I'm
here with Dr. Don Mucalem, our chief
medical officer at Fountain. Heart
disease has been personal for you as
well, hasn't it?
>> It really has, Peter. My daughter was
five, my husband died of sudden cardiac
death. And so, this is a topic that is
one that I am missiondriven to try to
eradicate. Prevention first and early
detection is absolutely critical. 50% of
people die of heart attacks with no
warning signs,
>> no shortness of breath, no pain, no
nothing.
>> No silent killer.
>> They just don't wake up in the morning.
they don't wake up and so you know AI
this is our mission to advance science
to try to help to one day democratize
wellness we know at fountain life when
we do this CT angography with AI
analytics we are actually finding that
88% of people coming in have detectable
coronary arter disease but Peter what's
more alarming to me is 23% of those
individuals had soft plaque this is the
plaque that would not traditionally be
seen on CT looking at calcium scores
alone and this is the plaque lack that
we must intervene with with the
multimodal testing we're doing,
including diagnostic laboratory studies
partnered with healthy lifestyle
recommendations.
>> So, listen, make sure you understand
what's going on inside your body
genetically, metabolically, and
cardiovascularly. You can know, and it's
your obligation to know. So, check it
out at fountainlife.com/peter
to find out more and really make sure
that you're the CEO of your own health.
All right, back to the episode. All
right. Uh, Michigan, over to you.
>> Thank you so much. Um, awesome to be
here. I want to give a quick shout out
to my wife, Melanie, who watched you
guys for a long time and then pushed me
over and over and over again to
following you [laughter]
>> and uh it's it's really been worthwhile.
So um my question is a little bit more
uh long-term but given that every tech
uh we know so far follows an S-curve uh
sort of development process. Um what do
you guys see on the horizon that's like
any fundamental new approach that comes
after LLMs?
>> Alex, that sounds like a
>> great question. This is a fun one.
>> I'm jealous. Alex, go for it. [laughter]
Well, first I I would distinguish
between LLMs and transformers. Uh LLMs
are just any models that are trying to
satisfy the language modeling task which
is predicting essentially predicting
next words. So I I think the
self-supervised task of next word, next
token, next bit prediction, I I think
that has effectively infinite longevity
to it. You can scale that task, the
self-supervised task from here to
solving everything. I'm not sure that we
need anything more, at least for AI,
than predicting the next bit or
predicting the missing bit. Even more
generally, it works pretty well. You can
again solve the mysteries of the
universe very well.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um you can generalize it, but I'm
not sure you need to. Whereas for say
transformers, Transformers, as I've
mentioned on the pod previously, are
being ship of thesis style, replaced bit
by bit. And if you look at the
transformers and the frontier models,
whether Chinese open weight or American
closed weight, they're mostly different
in in terms of the raw pieces from what
attention is all you need first came up
with. So yeah, in that sense, we're
we're already up some sort of sigmoid
curve.
>> But I don't know.
>> All right. Open that door. Not
>> can you do it in
>> I'm really curious now. Of course. All
>> [laughter]
>> right, I'll try and be really brief.
Look, like the the MLP part of the
current Transformers is identical to
what existed 20 or 30 years ago. So,
it's a it's pretty good bet that that's
going to be around. Um, the new thing,
the the old new thing is the residual
superighway where you're just modifying
a vector instead of recreating it every
layer. That's going to be around. The
new new thing, of course, is the
attention. But the more you dig in to
attention, it's more like a notebook
keeping notes than it is like a brain
function. And that that as a concept may
get radically restructured, but it'll
still be around as this kind of
knowledge accumulation notebook that's
sitting behind the ML or beside the MLP
at each layer. So I think all of those
structures are here to stay. I am 100%
sure that the compute substrate is going
to move to photonix and then after
physics gets reinvented by the current
AI it may move even quicker to something
else beyond that but you're looking at
the current infrastructure running
millions of times faster and then as
Alex said that's all that's going to
matter because it's going to think of
everything else after that and just
explain it to us. So I think and that's
all just in the next really 18 months to
two years is my guess. That's just
wicked exciting.
>> We could talk for hours about this, but
thank you for the question. I love this
topic.
>> Well,
I'll see you guys in LA, so maybe we can
take it up further.
>> Yeah, for sure.
>> Love to do that. Love to do that.
>> Moonshots live. It's going to be
amazing. All right. Uh, next up, Chris.
>> Hey guys. Um, been listening to the pod
a long time and I always listen to it at
like 1.5 or 1.75 speed. So, it's
interesting hearing you guys speak in
real time. Feel like I kind of downres
my my input here. Um, I'm I'm in in
Boulder, Colorado, and I'm using AI to
help improve the the dog care space,
recognizing patterns of behavior, etc.,
talking with pet parents. Um, but I'm
also because Sundance is coming here to
Boulder, I'm also hosting a series of
films. Um, and the last film that I
hosted was the AI doc, and we had about
150 people show up on a Friday night to
talk about both the film, but also sort
of their fears and thoughts about AI.
And when I was describing to the team,
to the crowd, how I listen to you guys,
because if you, you know, if you listen
to Eleazar or some of the other sort of
PDR crowd, you can get really anxious
and really sometimes even depressed. And
I describe you guys as like the upper
because you guys are so future uh
visionary and it's like positive and
it's it's a great energy um
>> sounding board against some of that
other stuff.
>> On a lot of your episodes you talk about
yes, we're going to have this period of
pain, right? We don't know what that
period of pain is going to look like.
And it feels like I don't really have
haven't yet discovered
good resources for understanding or how
to navigate that period of pain before
we get to the period of abundance.
>> Well, we're in the middle of it now. You
can see the current world order kind of
collapsing in front of us. Democracy is
breaking. Education is broken. All the
institutions, you know, there's about 50
institutions by which we run the world.
healthcare systems, legal systems,
intellectual property. We can't find one
that survives a tsunami of AI plus 20
other Gutenberg moments hitting us at
the same time. Right? Life extension
changes the world completely. AI very
clearly changes the world completely. We
we basically frame it that we have about
20 of these Gutenberg moments hitting us
at the same time. This is going to
radically force us to rethink all of
those institutions to a new model. And I
think that's bad in one way because that
change is very unpleasant and human
beings hate change as you we talk about
a lot. But I think it's good in which
it'll force us to rethink our
institutions from scarcity to what are
institutions that can n navigate an
abundance era. Right? And I think that's
the key question and we need to get a
large group of people focused on that.
We've been building with our exo
community now 50,000 people kind of a
peace core for the world that as we have
existing systems fail over we have a set
of people trained in that transformation
that period of uncertainty I think
started around 5 or 10 years ago and
it's going to go on for another 10 to 20
years it'll go like a peak and then
it'll uh and the question is can we
minimize that trough that's the question
>> yeah I I just add to that you know the
greatest concern I have is the the both
rational and but mostly irrational fear
that exists around AI. And we're going
to have challenges. You know, I'm not uh
you know, I'm optimistic in the long
run, right, for uh for humanity. And
we're going to have challenges. We're
going to have agents that not only break
out, we talked about that in the podcast
we recorded this morning. It's coming
out tomorrow. Uh but they're going to do
some harm. uh they're going to bring
down a power grid. They're going to, you
know, they're going to, you know, break
a bank in some fashion. And the reality
is, uh, every technology has caused harm
in one shape or form. But the good news
is, as Alex speaks to, it's, you know,
defensive co-scaling. Uh, you know, we
have so many zero day vulnerabilities in
code today because we humans wrote that
code. But that code is going to be
rewritten by AIS that don't leave these
vulnerabilities. And so there's a period
of you know two to eight years that I
talk about concern of civil unrest and I
wrote on on Substack about this. Most
all revolutions in the world happen from
young testosterone laden men who are
upset, angry. uh it might not be
rational why they're angry or maybe they
didn't get a job or they couldn't start
a family or things got too expensive and
at the end of the day we're you know
what is absolutely true is that we are
uplifting humanity we are demonetizing
and democratizing access to intelligence
energy longevity uh and these are all
good things for humanity and so we're
going to have rough spots I don't want
to be irrational about. There will be
rough spots and we will get through
them. So
>> what's amazing, Peter, is it's it's not
new in the world. You know, for my mom,
it was all the Cuban missile crisis and
they were taught to hide under desks and
everyone was building bomb shelters in
their basements and storing food and you
know, nuclear annihilation is imminent.
>> And then before that, you know, uh my
grandfather's generation FDR said the
only thing we have to fear is fear
itself. Well, he wouldn't have said that
if fear wasn't rampant at the time. So I
I think it's a common thing every recent
technological generation have this
moment of sheer anxiety.
>> And Dave, just to build on that, when
books for were first introduced in the
1500s, there was all these people
freaking out going, "It's going to
destroy our memory. It's going to create
the illusion of knowledge. It's going to
overwhelm people with information. It's
going to break them. It's going to
spread misinformation. It's going to
corrupt young people." Same pattern.
Same patterns. It happens every single
time we have major technological change,
>> right? This is the immune system.
>> Unless this is really the last
invention, right? And then you can't
[clears throat] repeat that.
>> We'll see.
>> Thank you guys.
>> That's why we call it a singularity. We
have no idea what's on the other side.
>> Some some of us do. I I guess for the
record, I I so in the book uh the last
invention, if if it's the same book I
remember, I think I was interviewed for
a chunk of that. For the record, I don't
think super intelligence is at least
human civilizations broadly construed
last invention. I think there are going
to be many, many inventions after super
intelligence. It's just that super
intelligence is going to invent andor
help us invent everything that comes
after it.
>> You guys do a great job. Thank you so
much.
>> And Chris, there's lots of love in the
chat for your artwork and behind you.
>> Oh, right on. Thanks. Thanks, guys.
All right, let's go to Ken Wilson next
and then we're going to have to wrap up
after that. I I promised my mates here
90 minutes if they'd give me more than
60. All right. Um our our final question
here.
>> Hey guys, uh huge fan of the pod. Keep
it up. Um just like everybody else has
said, we really appreciate what you guys
are doing. Uh I'm a partner in a small
niche comm coastal engineering firm. Uh
we specialize in coastal restoration
with background I've got a background in
geology and engineering and uh like it's
funny because our industry is one of
these where uh observational data is
really sparse compared to some other
places and uh we're trying to figure out
how to leverage that. But what I really
wanted to kind of ask you tonight um is
that that'll help me better calibrate
some of the feedback that you all got
give on the pod is um this qu question
kind of relates to a little bit of
worldview maybe dovtales into some of
what Chris was just talking about but
I'm wondering if any of you would
consider yourselves religious people and
do you leave any room in your analysis
for an all powerful all- knowing sort of
ultimate intelligence uh that has
intelligently designed the universe.
>> Fascinating question. Who wants to go
first?
>> I'll take that. Um, so if we are living
in a simulation, then somebody created
that simulation and that would be the uh
allseeing intelligence, right? Uh, so
that's path one. Uh, the other
alternative is that we have no we we
anthropomorphize and we invent our gods
and then we tend to believe in them.
There's clearly a lot of connective
energy amongst people. There's the
concept the Star Wars concept of of the
force and we then put images and labels
on that kind of a concept to u make
sense of the world because the for the
most of uh human history the world has
been a you know we lived brutish short
uh lives we created uh religions my
father used to say we invent our gods
and then we believe in them uh if you
look up John from and the cargo cults
you'll see a clear example of that uh in
where an entire religion sprung up
spontaneously uh out of this and we are
very uh apt to that. But as we get more
and more evidentiary basis for the
future then either the there is no god
and we're just moving towards a
wonderful future driven by technology or
there's a simulation and in which case
it kind of doesn't matter anyway.
>> Everybody I just want to say thank you
for your time. It's the most valuable
asset you have. Uh we love our community
and uh really appreciate you sharing uh
what we do with everybody. Um because
hopefully as you see we put a lot of
work into it and we love it. I I want to
thank my mates Alex and Dave and Salem
and Emmod.
>> Pleasure.
>> All the work that they do and our
production team uh to thank Nick and
Dana uh and Aiden and Gian Luca uh who
really support us, you know, 7 days, 24
hours a day. So again,
>> and Peter and Peter, thank you for
pulling all this together and forcing us
into this conversation. I think it's a
kicking and screaming in some cases, but
it's a joy. It's magnificently important
for the world.
>> And hopefully you guys all see the love
that we share amongst ourselves. My
favorite my favorite time of the week is
spending time with uh with my moonshot
mates. You know, the average of five
people. Yeah. Well, I get to hang out
with smarter people than I am. All
right, everybody. Uh we're going to be
doing this again uh in a evening
session. If you want to come again,
you're more than welcome to. Uh and
again, thank you. Hope to see you guys
at Moonshots Live. You can go to
moonshots.com to learn more. Uh, and
yeah, come and come and meet us in
person.
[music]